Eric Coleman

Software Engineer

SUMMARY

Software engineering consultant with strong focus on quick delivery of high quality software using modern engineering practices. Deep experience in DevOps tools and solutions. Wide ranging experience in many areas of software development including full stack web development, mobile development, and embedded software development. Accomplished public speaker with talks at local usergroups and conferences. Easy going personality with strong people skills. Avid, constant learner with a passion for sharing learning with colleagues.

PROFICIENCIES

Languages: Golang, Typescript, Elixir, Ruby, Bash/Shell scripting, JavaScript, Java, Clojure, C++, C#, plus many others at varying levels of expertise

Tools/Frameworks: Gitlab CI, Functional programming, React.js, Azure, Phoenix, Terraform, AWS, various test frameworks, Ansible, Jenkins, Spring, Vim, Git, Linux/OSX command line tools

Engineering Practices: Test Driven Development, Continuous Integration and Delivery, DevOps, Pair Programming, Agile Software Development

EXPERIENCE

Augustwenty, Columbus OH

Software Engineering Consultant

- o Path Robotics October 2021 to October 2022
 - Led client robot cell Software Bring Up team. Facilitated and coordinated efforts between client software, ops, controls, and hardware teams to help build, calibrate, and deploy robotic welding solutions. Tracked down and fixed bugs in bring up procedures, wrote documentation, and trained ops engineers to take over tasks from software teams. Onboarded client software staff.
- OliveAl April 2021 to October 2021
 - Developed and supported Desktop app and SDK, using Golang,
 Typescript, Electron, React. Consulted on and prototyped MacOS application code signing.
- Here Technologies November 2020 to Februrary 2021
 - Migrated client team's C++ build process from Jenkins CI / Gerrit to Gitlab
 CI
- Internal Designed, tested, and programmed Elixir/Phoenix web application utilizing external APIs for client prototype

- Internal Designed and implemented CI and DevOps processes for Elixir/Phoenix project and other internal efforts
- Internal Wrote Marketing copy and aided in deployment of company website.

Accenture Digital - Product X.0, Columbus OH

Senior Software Engineer - Prpl Team - April 2019 to June 2020

- o Built Software Defined Radio prototype for internal proof of concept
- Provided technical leadership on business development initiative for connected car prototype using in-vehicle edge devices communicating with Azure cloud services. Wrote edge device application using .NET Framework. Developed and tested messaging on in-vehicle CAN bus
- Designed and built Firebase backed React application and integrated application with custom hardware for a client proof of concept.
- Designed and deployed custom automotive demo. Demo included hardware integration
- Consulted on various internal prototypes

Pillar Technology, Columbus OH

Pillar Labs - March 2018 to April 2019

- Selected for team via internal application process
- Conducted research on various technologies as part of an internal initiative to get ahead of the kinds of tech clients are excited about. Prototyped and test drove exploratory code in widely varied tech stacks. Evaluated functionality and potential value of new tools.
- Designed and deployed indoor geolocation system. Test drove custom embedded sense software for peripheral devices using Python, a web backend using Phoenix, and a web frontend using React.js. Developed triangulation algorithms for interpretation of data.
- Automated deployment and provisioning process for
- Delivered Alexa integration and automated AWS infrastructure for automotive client
- Assembled and wrote code for embedded sensor device

Scientific Research Client: Infrastructure as a Service - April 2017 to March 2018

- Designed and implemented automated deployments for on-site cloud
- Managed private cloud infrastructure with OpenStack.
- Evaluated new technologies and tools to improve client tech stack

Finance/Banking Client: Credit Card Loyalty and Management App - March 2015 to April 2017

 Contributed code and added test suites to existing and new Android and iOS applications.

- Implemented Spring web application interfacing with client's card management services, designed to be added to retailer websites with minimal development work.
- Designed CI process and deployment pipeline to allow continuous deployment of new code to web server.
- Took on leadership role as primary DevOps engineer on site.
- Worked closely with Android and iOS development teams to design and implement robust CI pipeline, capable of creating various types of releases for QA and final release.
- Managed containerized team infrastructure including CI server (Jenkins), version control server (Bitbucket), dependency/artifact hosting (Nexus), internal app deployment (Hockey).
- Used Puppet and Boxen to configure development machines.
- Developed tools and environments for use by app developers.
- Forged relationships with various external teams to ensure access to necessary services and resources.

Agricultural Client: Mobile Build Pipeline - December 2014 to March 2015

- Designed and implemented CI infrastructure for iOS development team.
- Wrote test code and infrastructure management scripts.
- Learned to work with a remote team in a different timezone, including pair programming with on site developers.

Agricultural Client: Embedded Computer - June 2014 to December 2014

- Developed embedded application with C++ and Qt, running on internal computer in industrial farming vehicles
- o Utilized Linux development environments and learned command line tools
- Learned Agile team practices and XP engineering practices

SPEAKING ENGAGEMENTS

- Pillar Plugged In, May 2017 Tales of a DevOps Lone Ranger
- Columbus Code Camp 2016, Ohio DevFest 2016, Columbus GDG Mobile DevOps
- Columbus Clojure, April 2016 Programmable Music with Overtone
- Lightning talks on various topics including: Music Theory and production, Computer graphics and audio, Raycasting, Virtual Reality, Catapults

EDUCATION

Ohio University, Athens OH - 2010 to 2014

Associate Degree in Science

Completed coursework in Computer Science, Software Engineering